In Europe, Amazon operates in five marketplaces, including the United Kingdom, Germany, France,
Italy, and Spain.
If you are currently selling in the U.
S.
marketplace, selling in Europe with linked accounts and
build international listings tool simplifies the listing process and gives you the opportunity
to leverage Amazon's fulfillment network in Europe.
After your North American account and Europe account are linked.
You can select the U.
S.
as your source marketplace and add your offers to any of the five European
target marketplaces by using build international listings tool.
In order to take advantage of FBA programs in Europe, you need to ship your inventory
from the U.
S.
to an Amazon fulfillment center in Europe.
Also, your product needs to meet the rules, regulations, and laws of each European country.
For example, value added tax, also called VAT, in the European Union, is a consumption
tax assessed on the value added to your products and services.
It applies to products and services that are bought and sold for use or consumption in
the European Union.
The European consumers don't see a separate line item for tax.
Amazon's solution provider network, SPN, connects you with more than 100 high quality
solution providers who offer services such as shipping, VAT, product compliance, translation,
etc.
For more information, you can visit Amazon.
com/SPN.
After your products are delivered to an Amazon fulfillment center in Europe, you can fulfill
your orders across Europe through three international fulfillment programs.
In this video, you'll learn about the three international FBA services in Europe, which
make cross-border sales much easier to manage.
These three programs are Pan-European FBA, European fulfillment network, and multi-country inventory.
By enrolling in one of these programs, you're eligible for prime benefits, which gives you
the ability to ship products to customers with free standard shipping.
Now, let's take a look at the first program, Pan-European FBA.
Pan-European FBA is the ultimate in European sales solution.
With it, Amazon places your inventory at close proximity to your customers, providing faster
delivery, and growing your business quicker.
The Pan-European FBA program allows you to ship your inventory to one location, and Amazon
will distribute your inventory across the European fulfillment network based on anticipated customer
demand at no additional cost.
When a customer orders your products, you only pay local fulfillment fee of the marketplace
where the order is placed.
To use Pan-European FBA, simply enroll your eligible ASINs in the Pan-European FBA inventory
page.
You will be able to enroll eligible ASINs after you create an FBA offer in each of the Amazon
European marketplaces from the same inventory.
Activate ASIN auto-enrollment and Amazon will enroll eligible ASINs for you as soon as you
create the FBA offers.
To learn more, go to Seller Central in Europe and search Pan-European FBA in help.
The European fulfillment network, or EFN, is a good choice if you're just getting started
with selling in Europe.
EFN is a simple way to ship your inventory across all five of Amazon's European marketplaces.
Here's how it works.
First, you list the products in one or more of the Amazon European marketplaces with the
Build International listings tool.
Next, you ship your inventory to one of the fulfillment centers in Europe.
Then, customers across Europe can order your products, and Amazon fulfills those orders
from your Amazon inventory location.
When customers track their orders, they can see where they are shipping from, and the
expected arrival time.
For example, if you've shipped your products to a fulfillment center in the UK and a customer
in Germany purchases your product on Amazon.
de, the product is fulfilled by Amazon and shipped
from your inventory in that UK fulfillment center to Germany.
You pay UK to Germany cross-border fulfillment fee in addition to the Germany local FBA fulfillment
fee.
To learn more about EFN, sign in to Seller Central in Europe and search EFN in help.
So, what are the differences between Pan-European FBA and European Fulfillment Network?
First, Pan-European FBA requires selling in all five European marketplaces, while EFN
lets you choose up to five marketplaces.
Second, with Pan-European FBA, Amazon manages your inventory placement at no cost and moves
it across the Amazon European Fulfillment Network based on customer demand.
EFN, on the other hand, Amazon won't move your inventory out of the country where you
shipped your products to.
Finally, you only pay the local FBA fee with Pan-European, while there is an additional
cross-border fulfillment fee with EFN.
If you're not ready to sell to all marketplaces in Europe through Pan-European FBA and don't
want to pay the cross-border fulfillment fee through EFN, you can use the Multi-Country
Inventory, or MCI, program.
With MCI, you send your inventory directly to countries in Europe where customers are
buying, so your customers will receive your products quickly.
The differences between Pan-European FBA and Multi-Country Inventory are as follows.
First, Pan-European FBA requires selling in all five marketplaces, while you can choose
up to five EU marketplaces with MCI.
Second, with the Pan-European FBA service, you ship products to a single country, then
Amazon moves your inventory across the Amazon European Fulfillment Network at no cost.
With MCI services, you ship your products to Amazon in each country yourself.
Last, with the Pan-European FBA service, Amazon manages your inventory and moves it across
the Amazon European Fulfillment Network based on customer demand.
With the Multi-Country Inventory service, you have to identify how much inventory to
send to each country, and your inventory is stored only in the country you ship to.
That's all for this video.
Now you should have a good understanding of the three FBA international services in Europe.
If you want to learn more about the Fulfillment by Amazon services in Europe, go to services.
amazon.
co.
uk
and choose Fulfillment by Amazon.
To get started, click Sell globally below.
Happy selling!